Mss.Rec.253 Mss.Rec.253
American Philosophical Society
The Phonetics of Interior Salish
1993-1996
Mss.Rec.253
American Philosophical Society
4.0 Tape(s)
Linguistic field recordings in Vancouver, Lillooet, and Victoria, British Columbia, and Seattle. Elicitation of lexical items in five languages (Lillooet, Ntlakyapamuk, Gitksan, Nootka, and Tlingit) to record consonant-vowel interaction and unusual consonant types.
4 sound cassettes (3 hr., 26 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo.
Bessell, Nicola J.
Brown, Judson
Frank, Beverly
Louie, George
Ned, Bucky
Ned, Gertrude
Newton, Richard
Sennott, Barbara
Ursaki, Dorothy
Whitley, Rose
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by Nicola Bessell in February 1997. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Related Archival Materials
Fieldnotes and lexical lists used in recordings are available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Gitksan language; Lillooet language; Nootka language; Ntlakyapamuk language; Salishan languages; Sound recordings; Tlingit language
- Audio recordings
  - St'at'imcets (Lilloeet Salish) word list and lexical items, 1996-12-16; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:55; Bessell, Nicola; Ned, Bucky; Ned, Gertrude
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Lillooet (B.C.); Lillooet language
  - St'at'imcets (Lilloeet Salish) word list and lexical items [1 of 2], 1996-12-18; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:05; Bessell, Nicola; Frank, Beverly
  - St'at'imcets (Lilloeet Salish) word list and lexical items [2 of 2], 1996-12-18; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:22; Bessell, Nicola; Frank, Beverly
  - St'at'imcets (Lilloeet Salish) lexical items: #1-101, 1993-08-06; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:41; Bessell, Nicola; Whitley, Rose
  - St'at'imcets (Lilloeet Salish) lexical items: #102-171, 1993-08-06; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:56; Bessell, Nicola; Whitley, Rose
  - St'at'imcets (Lilloeet Salish) lexical items: #172-end, 1993-08-08; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:02; Bessell, Nicola; Whitley, Rose
  - Ntlakyapamuk (Thompson-Salish) lexical items, 1993-07-20; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:21; Bessell, Nicola; Ursaki, Dorothy
    Ntlakyapamuk language; Vancouver (B.C.)
  - Ahousaht (Nuuchahnulth: Nootka) word list & lexical items: #1-46, 1993-07-26; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:54; Bessell, Nicola; Louie, George
    Scope and Contents note
    The speaker speaks in the Ahousaht dialect of Nuu-chah-nulth.
    Nootka language; Victoria (B.C.)
  - Ahousaht (Nuuchahnulth: Nootka) word list & lexical items: #48-end, 1993-08-12; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:52; Bessell, Nicola; Louie, George
  - Gitksan word list and lexical items: #1-53, 1993-08-09; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:37; Bessell, Nicola; Sennott, Barbara
    Gitksan language; Vancouver (B.C.)
  - Gitksan word list and lexical items: #54-114, 1993-08-16; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:26; Bessell, Nicola; Sennott, Barbara
  - Gitksan word list and lexical items: #115-123, 1993-08-17; 03-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:50; Bessell, Nicola; Sennott, Barbara
  - Gitksan word list and lexical items: #124-end, 1993-08-17; 03-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:27; Bessell, Nicola; Sennott, Barbara
  - Tlingit word list and lexical items: #1-73, 1994-07-30; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:24; Bessell, Nicola; Newton, Richard
    The speaker was born in Kake, Alaska, with Tlingit as his first language. He speaks in a transitional dialect of Tlingit.
    Seattle (Wash.); Tlingit language
  - Tlingit word list and lexical items: #74-142, 1994-07-31; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:45; Bessell, Nicola; Newton, Richard
  - Tlingit word list and lexical items: #142 continuation and short speech, 1994-07-31; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:15; Bessell, Nicola; Newton, Richard
  - Tlingit word list and lexical items: #144-end, 1994-08-02; 04-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:21; Bessell, Nicola; Newton, Richard
  - Tlingit word list and lexical items: #1-end, 1994-08-01; 04-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:43; Bessell, Nicola; Brown, Judson
    The speaker speaks in the northern dialect of Tlingit.